Federal Art Project, Photographic Division
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Federal Art Project, Photographic Division collection
circa 1920-1965, bulk 1935-1942
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Federal Art Project. Photographic Division
12.4 linear feet
The Federal Art Project, Photographic Division collection dates from circa 1920-1965, with the bulk of the records spanning the active years of the Federal Art Project (FAP), 1935-1942. The collection comprises 12.4 linear feet of mostly photographic prints and negatives that document primarily artwork produced by artists employed by the FAP. A smaller number of photographs also document other programs of the FAP, such as art classes and community centers, exhibitions by children and adults, artwork installed in public buildings, project divisions, and demonstrations of art processes by FAP artists.
Provenance
The collection was donated anonymously sometime in the late 1950s.
Related Material
Among the holdings of the Archives of American Art are related collections, including the Federal Art Project of the Work Projects Administration records, 1935-1948. Additional FAP records are held by the National Archives and Records Administration in Washington D.C.
Alternative Forms Available
This collection is also available on 35 mm microfilm reels 1160-1174 at Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of the collection as described in this finding aid may not reflect the order of the collection on microfilm.
Restrictions on Access
Use of originals requires an appointment.
Historical Note
The Federal Art Project (FAP) was one of the depression-era work relief programs of the Federal Works Progress Administration (WPA). The program was founded in August 1935 to provide employment for artists and to implement visual arts programs in local communities across the country.
Together with the Federal Music Project, the Federal Theater Project and the Federal Writers' Project the FAP formed part of the WPA's Federal Project No. 1. The WPA became the Work Projects Administration in 1939 when it fell under the administrative hand of the newly created Federal Works Agency; concurrently the Federal Art Project was officially re-named the Federal Art Program.
Under the direction of Holger Cahill, the goals of the FAP fell into three main areas: production of artwork, art education through art classes and community centers, and art research through the Index of American Design. During the course of the program, artists created murals and other artwork for many for non-Federal government buildings such as schools, hospitals and libraries. Separate photographic divisions were set up in several states, most notably in New York City, to document the work of artists employed by the program, activities in art education such as classes for children and adults and community center outreach programs, and other "Federal One" projects including the Federal Theater and Music Projects. Employees of the photographic division were also involved in creative assignments such as exhibitions and photo murals.
The FAP ended in 1943.
Scope and Content Note
The Federal Art Project, Photographic Division collection dates from circa 1920-1965, with the bulk of the records spanning the active years of the Federal Art Project (FAP), 1935-1942. The collection comprises 12.4 linear feet of mostly photographic prints and negatives. Artist files comprise approximately three-quarters of the collection and contain photographs of artwork by artists involved in the FAP in addition to some photographs of the artists themselves.
The remainder of the collection consists of files documenting related activities and programs of the FAP arranged by subject. The bulk of these files document the activities of the New York City FAP including free art classes and art exhibitions for adults and children, exhibitions at the Harlem Art Center, and the work of FAP branches including the Easel Division, the Graphic Arts Division and the Poster Division.
Also found here are photographs of federal and community art centers in eleven other states (most extensively Washington State) and other WPA projects such as the Federal Theater, Music and Writer's projects, in addition to buildings decorated with FAP artwork, photographs of artists demonstrating art processes, and photographs of special events and people involved with the FAP.
One folder contains images that appear to have been taken by Berenice Abbott for the exhibition Changing New York, for the Museum of the City of New York in collaboration with the WPA.
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Federal Art Project -- Photographs; Federal Music Project U.S. -- Photographs; Federal Theatre Project U.S. -- Photographs; Federal Writers' Project U.S. -- Photographs
Subjects-Topical:
Artists -- United States -- Photographs; Federal aid to the arts -- Photographs; Art and state -- United States -- Photographs; New Deal, 1933-1939 -- Photographs; Federal aid to the public welfare -- Photographs; Theater and state -- United States -- Photographs; Music and state -- United States -- Photographs; African American artists -- New York (State) -- New York -- Photographs; Children's art -- United States -- Photographs; Art -- United States -- Exhibitions -- Photographs; Art -- United States -- Study and teaching -- Photographs; Hispanic American artists; Art festivals
Types of Materials:
Photographs
Names:
Abbott, Berenice, 1898- -- Changing New York; United States. Works Progress Administration; United States. Work Projects Administration
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 2 series:
Series 1: Artist Files, circa 1920-1965 (Boxes 1-24; 9.6 linear feet)
Series 2: Subject Files, 1935-1942 (Boxes 25-31; 2.8 linear feet)
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Artist Files, circa 1920-1965, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-24; 9.6 linear feet)
  This series consists primarily of photographs of artwork produced by FAP artists, in addition to scattered photographs of artists and other individuals engaged in FAP work or attending FAP events. An attempt has been made to date photographs using dates provided on the back of the photos where these exist, although it should be noted that those dates may not accurately indicate the date on which copy prints were produced. In the case of undated material a date of "circa 1935-circa 1942" is assigned to the folder, since it can reasonably be assumed that most photographs were taken within this time period. A few items pre-date or post-date the existence of the FAP.
  Photographs are arranged alphabetically by name of artist. Folders containing photos of artists are indicated at the folder title. When known, microfilm reel or microfilm reel/frame information is provided in parentheses with folder titles.
  - Abbate, Paolo S., circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 1)
  - Abbenseth, William, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 2)
  - Abelman, Ida, 1936-1940, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 3)
  - Abernathy, Inez, 1939, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 4)
  - Abramovitz, Albert, circa 1935-circa 1940, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 5)
  - Abramson, Hershel, 1937-1939, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 6)
  - Adams, Charles, 1939, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 7)
  - Adler, Fred, 1939, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 8)
  - Adler, Joseph, 1937-1941, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 9)
  - Afroyim, Beys, 1937-1938, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 10)
  - Aguado, Hyman, 1939, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 11)
  - Ajay, Abraham, 1939, 1941, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 12)
  - Albrizio, Humbert, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 13)
  - Albro, Maxine, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 14)
  - Alexandrovich, Albert, 1937, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 15)
  - Alger, John, 1937-1940, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 16)
  - Alland, Alexander, 1936-1939, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 17)
  - Allen, John, 1938, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 18)
  - Aloisi, Anna, 1938, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 19)
  - Alshets, Simon, 1936-1941, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 20)
    includes photo of Alshets, 1938 August
  - Alston, Charles, circa 1938-circa 1939, (R: 1160) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 21)
    includes photos of Alston, 1939
  - Ambellan, Harold, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 22)
  - Amero, Emilio, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 23)
  - Ames, Grace Greenwood, 1939, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 24)
  - Anchel, Harold, circa 1937-circa 1941, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 25)
  - Anderson, Carlos, 1938-1941, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 26)
  - Angel, Rifka, 1939-1941, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 27)
  - Angell, Blanche, 1939-1941, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 28)
  - Annunziata, Nicoli, 1937-1941, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 29)
  - Arcamonte, Humbert, 1938-1939, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 30)
  - Archer, Robert, 1938-1941, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 31)
  - Arenal, Luis, circa 1936-circa 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 32)
    includes photos of Arenal, 1936
  - Arkavi, M. H., circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 33)
  - Arms, John Taylor, 1941, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 34)
  - Arnold, A. Grant, 1938, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 35)
  - Artman, Jean, 1941, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 36)
  - Ashe, Edmund, circa 1937-circa 1939, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 37)
  - Ashley, James, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 38)
  - Atkins, Florence Elizabeth, 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 39)
  - Atkinson, John Ingliss, 1940, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 40)
  - Ault, George C., 1939-1941, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 41)
  - Austin, Darrel, circa 1934-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 42)
  - Austin, Ralph, circa 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 43)
  - Ausubel, Sheva, 1937-1941, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 44)
    includes photos of Ausubel, 1937-1938
  - Avery, Frances, circa 1937-circa 1938, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 45)
  - Avery, Milton, 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 46)
  - Baccante, Enzo, 1936, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 47)
  - Bacharach, Herman I., 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 48)
  - Bagis, 1941, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 49)
  - Bahnmuller, W., 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 50)
  - Baizerman, Eugenie, 1938, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 51)
  - Bakos, Josef, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 52)
  - Ball, F. Carlton, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 53)
  - Bannarn, Henry Wilmer, circa 1937-circa 1938, (R: 1161) (Box 1 (hol), Folder 54)
    includes photos of Bannarn
  - Barbarossa, Theodore Cotillo, circa 1938, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 1)
  - Barbu, Elena, circa 1936-circa 1941, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 2)
  - Bard, Philip, 1939-1941, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 3)
  - Barela, Patrocino, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 4)
    includes photos of Barela, circa 1936
  - Barnet, Will, circa 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 5)
  - Barone, Antonio, 1937-1938, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 6)
  - Barr, N., 1940, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 7)
  - Barrows, Charles, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 8)
  - Barthe, Richmond, 1939, 1941, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 9)
    includes photo of Barthe, 1941
  - Barto, Emily Newton, 1937-1938, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 10)
    includes photo of Barto, 1937 October
  - Bartsch, 1941, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 11)
  - Bateman, John, 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 12)
  - Bates, Isabel, 1937-1941, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 13)
    includes photo of Bates
  - Bates, Kenneth, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 14)
  - Baum, Mark, circa 1937-circa 1941, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 15)
  - Baum, Max, circa 1937-circa 1941, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 16)
  - Baumann, Gustave, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 17)
  - Baumbach, Harold, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 18)
  - Bawler, H. J., 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 19)
  - Bayard, Lucy (Lucie), 1940, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 20)
  - Baziotes, William, 1941, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 21)
  - Beach, 1941, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 22)
  - Beach, Beata, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 23)
  - Beauchamp, John W., circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 24)
  - Beck, Morris, 1937-1941, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 25)
  - Becker, Frederick W., 1936-1940, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 26)
  - Becker, Samuel, 1940-1941, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 27)
  - Bedford, Enea, circa 1939, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 28)
  - Bekker, David, 1938, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 29)
  - Bell, Clara Louise, 1938, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 30)
  - Bell, Enid, 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 31)
  - Belsor, L. H., 1938, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 32)
  - Beman, Roff, 1940, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 33)
  - Bengelsdont, Rosalind, 1938, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 34)
  - Benn, Ben, 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 35)
  - Bennett, Rainey, 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 36)
  - Ben-Shmuel, Ahron, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 37)
  - Benson, John, circa 1938, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 38)
    includes photo of Benson, 1938 May
  - Bentley, John W., 1938, 1941, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 39)
  - Bentz, John, 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 40)
  - Berger, Andrew, circa 1935-circa 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 41)
    includes photo of Berger, 1936 April
  - Bergere, Frederick, 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 42)
  - Berlow, 1940, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 43)
  - Berman, Sarah, 1936-1939, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 44)
  - Berman, Saul, circa 1940-circa 1941, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 45)
  - Berninghaus, Charles T., circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 46)
  - Bernstein, Morris Louis, 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 47)
  - Biafora, Enea, circa 1936-circa 1941, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 48)
  - Biddle, George, circa 1936, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 49)
    photo of Biddle, 1936
  - Bigelow, Barbara, circa 1936, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 50)
  - Billings, Henry, circa 1940, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 51)
  - Bishop, Isabel, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 52)
  - Bissell, Cleveland, 1939, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 53)
  - Bisttram, Emil, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 54)
  - Bjorn, Aleth C., 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 55)
  - Black, Harold, circa 1937-circa 1941, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 56)
  - Blanch, Arnold, circa 1937, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 57)
  - Blanch, Lucille, 1940, (R: 1161) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 58)
    includes photo of Blanch, 1940 October
  - Blazy, Sterling, 1937-1939, (R: 1162) (Box 2 (hol), Folder 59)
  - Bloch, Julius, 1936, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 1)
  - Bloch, Lucienne, circa 1936-circa 1938, (R: 1161) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 2)
    includes photos of Bloch, circa 1938
  - Block, Irving, 1940-1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 3)
  - Block, Paul, circa 1935-circa 1938, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 4)
  - Blumenau, Lili, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 5)
  - Blumenfeld, Maurice, circa 1937-circa 1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 6)
  - Bodin, Paul, 1940-1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 7)
  - Bolotowsky, Ilya, circa 1937-circa 1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 8)
    includes photos of Bolotowsky, circa 1938-circa 1939
  - Bolton, Clarence, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 9)
  - Bonamico, S., circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 10)
  - Booth, Cameron, 1940, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 11)
  - Borghi, Guido, 1937-1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 12)
  - Borne, Mortimer, 1938, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 13)
  - Botke, Jessie Arms, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 14)
  - Botts, Hugh Pearce, circa 1937-circa 1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 15)
  - Bouché, Louis, 1940, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 16)
  - Bowden, Harry, 1936, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 17)
  - Bowes, Julian, circa 1937-circa 1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 18)
  - Bowler, Harold, 1938-1939, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 19)
  - Boyd, Byron B., circa 1936, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 20)
  - Boyd, Douglas, 1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 21)
  - Boylos, Selma, 1937, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 22)
  - Boynton, Ray, circa 1936, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 23)
  - Brackman, Robert, circa 1940, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 24)
  - Brandfield, Dayton, 1938-1940, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 25)
  - Brann, Louise, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 26)
    includes photos of Brann, circa 1936
  - Braun, Clayton, 1937-1939, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 27)
  - Breidvik, Mons, circa 1936-circa 1937, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 28)
  - Breinin, Raymond, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 29)
  - Brennecke, Muriel, circa 1937-circa 1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 30)
  - Breslow, Louis, 1940-1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 31)
  - Brigante, Nicholas, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 32)
  - Briggs, Judson, circa 1937-circa 1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 33)
  - Brindesi, Olympio, circa 1936-circa 1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 34)
  - Brisman, Hyman, circa 1936-circa 1937, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 35)
  - Brockman, Ann, circa 1936, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 36)
  - Brodsky, George, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 37)
  - Brody, Laws, 1938, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 38)
  - Bromberg, Manuel, 1939, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 39)
    photos of Bromberg
  - Brooks, Eve, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 40)
  - Brooks, James, circa 1937-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 41)
    includes photo of Brooks, 1940 August
  - Brown, Helen, 1937-1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 42)
  - Brown, Robert A., 1939-1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 43)
  - Browne, Byron, circa 1936-circa 1940, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 44)
  - Bruce, Edward, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 45)
  - Brussel-Smith, Bernard, 1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 46)
  - Buck, Bennett, 1940, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 47)
  - Burchfield, Charles, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 48)
  - Burke, David, 1941, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 49)
  - Burke, Selma, circa 1925-circa 1938, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 50)
    includes photos of Burke
  - Burlin, Paul, circa 1940, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 51)
  - Burlingame, Dennis, circa 1939, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 52)
  - Burliuk, David D., 1937, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 53)
  - Burstyn, Jerome, 1937, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 54)
  - Busa, Peter, 1940, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 55)
  - Buzzelli, Joseph A., 1939, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 56)
  - Byer, Alexander, 1937-1938, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 57)
  - Byron, Redman, 1937, (R: 1162) (Box 3 (hol), Folder 58)
  - Caesar, Doris Porter, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 1)
  - Caffey, Neva, 1938-1939, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 2)
  - Calapai, Letterio, circa 1937-circa 1939, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 3)
    includes photos of Calapai, circa 1937
  - Campanella, Vincent, 1937-1938, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 4)
  - Campbell, Alice, circa 1936-circa 1938, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 5)
  - Campbell, Blendon, 1937-1939, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 6)
  - Canadé, Vincent, circa 1937-circa 1940, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 7)
  - Cardona, Marguerite, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 8)
  - Caredio, Primo, 1940, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 9)
  - Cartaino, Paolo, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 10)
  - Cash, Harold, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 11)
  - Cassidy, Gerald, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 12)
  - Catenaro, Armand, circa 1939-circa 1941, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 13)
  - Cavallon, Giorgio, 1937-1938, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 14)
  - Cederquist, Arthur E., circa 1939, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 15)
  - Celentano, Daniel, circa 1937-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 16)
  - Cerny, George, 1941, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 17)
  - Cervantez, Pedro, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 18)
    includes photo of Cervantez
  - Champanier, Abram August, circa 1936-circa 1940, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 19)
  - Chan, H., 1941, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 20)
  - Chanase, Dane, circa 1937-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 21)
    includes photos of Chanase, circa 1942
  - Chaney, Ruth, circa 1938-circa 1940, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 22)
  - Chapin, Cornelia Van Auken, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 23)
  - Charat, Bernard S., 1939, (R: 1162) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 24)
  - Charlot, Jean, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 25)
  - Chavez, Edward, 1940, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 26)
  - Cheney, Philip, 1936, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 27)
  - Chernoff, Vadim, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 28)
  - Chin, Chee, 1937, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 29)
  - Chodorow, Eugene, circa 1937-circa 1939, 1965, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 30)
    includes photos of Chodorow and August Henkel, circa 1939
  - Christopher, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 31)
  - Citron, Minna, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 32)
  - Claflin, Majel G., circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 33)
  - Claney, Howard, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 34)
  - Clark, Fletcher, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 35)
  - Cogan, Martin, 1938-1939, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 36)
  - Cohen, Toby, circa 1936-circa 1939, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 37)
  - Cole, Robert B., 1936-1941, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 38)
  - Cole, Thomas Casilear, 1937-1941, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 39)
  - Colgan, Joseph, circa 1937-circa 1939, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 40)
  - Collins, Pat, 1939, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 41)
    photo of Collins, 1939 April
  - Collins, Rosamond, 1937, (R: 1163) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 42)
  - Connaway, Jay H., 1940, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 1)
  - Constant, George, circa 1938-circa 1941, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 2)
  - Cook, Howard, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 3)
  - Cooke, Regina Tatum, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 4)
  - Copeland, Lila, 1938-1940, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 5)
  - Copen, Herman, 1938, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 6)
  - Corbino, Jon, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 7)
  - Cormis, Jack, 1937, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 8)
  - Corso, Antonio, 1938-1939, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 9)
  - Cosgrave, John O'Hara, 1940, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 10)
  - Costa, Francis, circa 1937-circa 1940, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 11)
    includes photo of Costa, 1939
  - Couse, E., circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 12)
  - Covey, Arthur, circa 1935-circa 1942, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 13)
  - Cox, George, 1938-1941, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 14)
  - Craig, Martin, circa 1936-circa 1940, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 15)
  - Crimi, Alfred D., circa 1941, (R: 1163) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 16)